hey what's up guys my name is occiano
and today i wanted to answer a question
that i get asked
very often what do i do next in my
c-plus plus learning journey
now this is a very common and fair
question i've been teaching simple spots
on youtube for quite a few years now
i've also been teaching students
one-on-one privately as well and they
seem to get through all of this teaching
content
rather easily whether it be my videos
whether it be cpus plus textbooks or
even university courses they have no
trouble learning the concepts from all
of our content as well as even
setting exams but what do you do next
what do you do once you've been taught
c plus so to speak how do you transition
into actually being able to
write c plus plus code freely and more
or less
speak c plus plus fluently if you may
i'm going to sum this up in just a
single phrase for you right here so it's
really nice and simple
open source projects you need to start
looking
at other people's code actual real world
c
plus code not examples in textbooks not
the kind of
homework that you get from the your
university software engineering course
no you need to start looking at actual
projects
in the real world i mean think about it
when you're sitting there in a code
interview
and the person wants to hire you and you
want to be hired
what kind of code do they expect you to
write examples on how to implement a
vector or a list or something like that
or actual real-world code that belongs
inside their code base well of course
they're going to want the latter they'll
train you in the job don't get me wrong
i'm sure you'll pick up a lot
of stuff during your job you're not
expected to know everything
upon being hired but you need to
understand
how software is actually written and
what real world code looks like
now this is actually how i learn
at the level that i'm at whatever level
that is i like to read other people's
code whenever there's some new concept
or a new problem or a new technique or a
new algorithm or just something that's
new to me
my favorite way of learning that is to
actually look at existing code that's
out there
because i speak c or i speak programming
if you will
and so it's a lot easier for me to
actually read about it natively in that
language rather than hear someone
actually
want to describe a concept in english
because that just doesn't make as much
sense to me now for people who aren't
quite sure what i'm saying
here i like to compare this to real
world languages
assuming you know english maybe you're
trying to learn a language like german
or japanese or something like that
i mean sure you'll sit down you'll do
the course maybe you'll learn about it
in university or in high school or
something like that
you know you've got grammar textbooks
you've got little exercises and exams
that you can write
but you can't live off of that you can't
learn the language fluently
just off of that kind of material you
need to actually start consuming media
such as like watching tv shows movies
stuff like that in the language that you
want to learn maybe even change your
phone over into that language
so that you're forced to actually learn
about all these new words that might
have
have stuff to do with phones
specifically or other media you have to
immerse yourself in that world and in
fact moving to the country whose
language you're trying to learn
so moving to like germany or something
like that will help you
a lot more it stops being about being
taught that specific language and it
starts being more about being in that
environment
right and it's the same thing with c
plus you don't need someone to teach you
c plus after a while once you've learned
the basics once you've learned certain
things
i mean sure you can come back and you
can keep learning more about it
but after a certain point you need to
actually
start using c plus plus and actually
immerse yourself in a world of c-plus
plus you know like work
somewhere where they're using c plus
plus or if you don't have a job then
maybe
start looking at open source projects as
i mentioned and start contributing to
them because
if you immerse yourself in the language
that you're trying to learn and actually
start using it as if you already know
the language
forcing yourself to actually learn more
about it then you're going to do
a lot better so what projects should you
start looking at
well my advice is always to start
looking at something that interests you
so if you're really into games maybe
look for some open source game projects
on github
something maybe simple like mario to
start off with or any arcade games from
the 80s they're really good places to
start but then you can gradually build
that as well
maybe you're interested in game engines
well take a look at unreal engine or go
dot
engine or even my engine hazel and if
none of that stuff interests you maybe
you're interested in actually helping
the world
in your quest to immerse yourself more
in c plus why not check out one of the
bug bounty programs these basically pay
you money to try and find
problems or issues or bugs inside c plus
plus code but what stage do i need to be
to dive into this kind of stuff now this
varies from person to person because i
know a lot of people get overwhelmed
looking at
actual real world projects if it's a
little bit too early but i would say
don't worry about it just check it out
anyway it's usually not gonna do any
harm
i mean think of it like moving to japan
without speaking much
japanese you're going to pick it up if
you live there that's
in fact probably the best way to pick it
up now personally i love using a tool
called pbs studio who are also the
sponsors of this video
while i'm looking through all of these
massive projects pbs studio is a static
analyzer which is going to help
point out problems in source code i mean
seriously having pbs studio open while
i'm looking through
this kind of new foreign source code
that i've never seen before
is a really informative experience
because it points out areas that first
of all i would never
just detect or pick up on but also
looking at
serious projects even struggling with
errors and seeing what they did wrong
can actually help improve your code by
quite a bit let's take a look at an
example project we'll take a look at
opencv
it's an optical recognition framework
that's pretty popular for trying to
recognize
objects or text from images first let's
quickly obtain it and actually
build it on our computer so we'll clone
it from github
and then run cmake to generate our
visual studio project files and then
finally we can open it and actually give
it a build
as well as check out what pbs studio has
to say about its code base
because this is such a huge code base i
personally like to just check the
current file for errors so we'll find a
file that we
are interested in and just scan through
to see if pvs studio finds any issues
with it
and as you can see there are plenty now
some of these of course aren't
huge deals i love the fact that pbs
studio actually triages them so we've
got these red ones as like
really the ones you probably want to
take a look at first and take a look at
this
macro issue here for example pbs studio
tells us that
this if statement is not necessary if we
take a look at it we can see that the
macro itself
actually includes an if statement so
having two if statements two branches
like that
is totally unnecessary learning from
this we now know that it's just
something to keep in the back of our
minds
if you're writing a macro that has an if
statement make sure you're not also
checking for the condition outside of
the macro because
the macro takes care of it all of these
little things here and there add up to
just having more experience in c
plus and that's something that's
incredibly beneficial to both your own
programming as well as to
someone potentially hiring you so long
story short
immerse yourselves in as many c plus
plus projects as you can
if you want to actually pick up real
world c plus plus a lot faster i think
it's the perfect next step
once you know the basics of the language
you know how things work you at least
know how to build a project
you'll get to see more than just c plus
plus code as well and how it's written
you'll see how
projects actually come together how the
build system works
why they might be using something like
cmake and not just visual studio itself
there's so much to learn from
experiencing real world projects so
definitely check it out now as i
mentioned pbs studio is a fantastic
companion to have
along with you for this journey i'll
leave a link in the description below
where you can check out a free trial of
pbs studio and try it out for free
for yourselves i think it's definitely a
really useful tool to have
and i mean you might as well try it out
for free i'll also leave a link to some
more information about the bug bounty
program and how pbs studio can actually
help you out with that as well it's a
really interesting read definitely take
a look at that in the description below
anyway i hope you guys enjoyed this
video if you did please don't forget to
hit that like button below if you go on
to try out some of these open source
projects then please let me know how you
go and if that helps you out
and i will see you next time goodbye
[Music]
you